The U.S. is tied for 15th in reading, but we're 23rd in science and 31st in math. So there's really only one area where we're near the top, and that's in failing to give our teachers the help they need to develop their skills. Let's look at the best academic performer: the province of Shanghai, China. Now, they rank number one across the board, in reading, math and science, and one of the keys to Shanghai's incredible success is the way they help teachers keep improving. They made sure that younger teachers get a chance to watch master teachers at work. They have weekly study groups, where teachers get together and talk about what's working. They even require each teacher to observe and give feedback to their colleagues. You might ask, why is a system like this so important? It's because there's so much variation in the teaching profession. Some teachers are far more effective than others. In fact, there are teachers throughout the country who are helping their students make extraordinary gains. If today's average teacher could become as good as those teachers, our students would be blowing away the rest of the world. So we need a system that helps all our teachers be as good as the best. What would that system look like? Well, to find out, our foundation has been working with 3,000 teachers in districts across the country on a project called Measures of Effective Teaching. We had observers watch videos of teachers in the classroom and rate how they did on a range of practices. For example, did they ask their students challenging questions? Did they find multiple ways to explain an idea? We also had students fill out surveys with questions like, "Does your teacher know when the class understands a lesson?" "Do you learn to correct your mistakes?" And what we found is very exciting. First, the teachers who did well on these observations had far better student outcomes. So it tells us we're asking the right questions. And second, teachers in the program told us that these videos and these surveys from the students were very helpful diagnostic tools, because they pointed to specific places where they can improve. I want to show you what this video component of MET looks like in action. (Music) (Video) Sarah Brown Wessling: Good morning everybody. Let's talk about what's going on today. To get started, we're doing a peer review day, okay? A peer review day, and our goal by the end of class is for you to be able to determine whether or not you have moves to prove in your essays. My name is Sarah Brown Wessling. I am a high school English teacher at Johnston High School in Johnston, Iowa. Turn to somebody next to you. Tell them what you think I mean when I talk about moves to prove. I've talk about -- I think that there is a difference for teachers between the abstract of how we see our practice and then the concrete reality of it. Okay, so I would like you to please bring up your papers. I think what video offers for us is a certain degree of reality. You can't really dispute what you see on the video, and there is a lot to be learned from that, and there are a lot of ways that we can grow as a profession when we actually get to see this. I just have a flip camera and a little tripod and invested in this tiny little wide-angle lens. At the beginning of class, I just perch it in the back of the classroom. It's not a perfect shot. It doesn't catch every little thing that's going on. But I can hear the sound. I can see a lot. And I'm able to learn a lot from it. So it really has been a simple but powerful tool in my own reflection. All right, let's take a look at the long one first, okay? Once I'm finished taping, then I put it in my computer, and then I'll scan it and take a peek at it. If I don't write things down, I don't remember them. So having the notes is a part of my thinking process, and I discover what I'm seeing as I'm writing. I really have used it for my own personal growth and my own personal reflection on teaching strategy and methodology and classroom management, and just all of those different facets of the classroom. I'm glad that we've actually done the process before so we can kind of compare what works, what doesn't. I think that video exposes so much of what's intrinsic to us as teachers in ways that help us learn and help us understand, and then help our broader communities understand what this complex work is really all about. I think it is a way to exemplify and illustrate things that we cannot convey in a lesson plan, things you cannot convey in a standard, things that you cannot even sometimes convey in a book of pedagogy. Alrighty, everybody, have a great weekend. I'll see you later. [Every classroom could look like that] (Applause) Bill Gates: One day, we'd like every classroom in America to look something like that. But we still have more work to do. Diagnosing areas where a teacher needs to improve is only half the battle. We also have to give them the tools they need to act on the diagnosis. If you learn that you need to improve the way you teach fractions, you should be able to watch a video of the best person in the world teaching fractions. So building this complete teacher feedback and improvement system won't be easy. For example, I know some teachers aren't immediately comfortable with the idea of a camera in the classroom. That's understandable, but our experience with MET suggests that if teachers manage the process, if they collect video in their own classrooms, and they pick the lessons they want to submit, a lot of them will be eager to participate. Building this system will also require a considerable investment. Our foundation estimates that it could cost up to five billion dollars. Now that's a big number, but to put it in perspective, it's less than two percent of what we spend every year on teacher salaries. The impact for teachers would be phenomenal. We would finally have a way to give them feedback, as well as the means to act on it. But this system would have an even more important benefit for our country. It would put us on a path to making sure all our students get a great education, find a career that's fulfilling and rewarding, and have a chance to live out their dreams. This wouldn't just make us a more successful country. It would also make us a more fair and just one, too. I'm excited about the opportunity to give all our teachers the support they want and deserve. I hope you are too. Thank you. (Applause)
EE.UU. empata en lectura en el puesto 15, pero en ciencia es el 23, y en matemática el 31. Solo hay un área en la que estamos casi en la cima, y es en no dar a nuestros profesores la ayuda necesaria para que desarrollen sus habilidades. Analicemos los sistemas que tienen mejor rendimiento académico: la provincia de Shanghái, China. Ocupa el primer lugar en todas las áreas: en lectura, matemática y ciencias, y una de las claves del éxito increíble de Shanghái es la forma en la que promueve la mejora en los profesores. Se aseguran de que los profesores más jóvenes tengan la oportunidad de ver trabajar a profesores magistrales. Tienen grupos de estudio semanales donde se reúnen los profesores a hablar de lo que funciona. Incluso solicitan que cada profesor analice y dé retroalimentación a sus colegas. Se preguntarán por qué es tan importante un sistema así. Porque en la enseñanza hay mucha variabilidad. Algunos profesores son mucho más efectivos que otros. De hecho, hay profesores en todo el país que ayudan a sus estudiantes a obtener logros extraordinarios. Si hoy el profesor medio llegase a igualar a esos profesores, nuestros estudiantes arrasarían al resto del mundo. Por eso necesitamos un sistema que ayude a nuestros profesores a ser lo mejor de lo mejor. ¿Cómo sería ese sistema? Bueno, para averiguarlo, nuestra fundación ha trabajado con 3000 profesores en distritos de todo el país en un proyecto llamado Métricas de la Enseñanza Eficaz [MEE]. Pusimos observadores a ver videos de profesores en el aula para que los calificaran en una serie de prácticas. Por ejemplo, ¿le hicieron a sus estudiantes preguntas estimulantes? ¿Encontraron múltiples formas de explicar una idea? También le pedimos a los estudiantes que respondieran un cuestionario: "¿Sabe tu profesor cuándo la clase entiende una lección?" "¿Aprendes a corregir tus errores?" Y hallamos cosas interesantes. Primero, los profesores a los que les fue bien obtenían mucho mejores resultados estudiantiles. Eso nos dicta que hicimos las preguntas correctas. Y, segundo, los profesores del programa nos dijeron que estos videos y encuestas de los alumnos fueron herramientas de diagnóstico muy útiles, porque señalaron lugares específicos que podían mejorarse. Quiero mostrarles este video del MEE en acción. (Música) (Video) Sarah Brown Wessling: Buenos días a todos. Hablemos de lo que haremos hoy. Para empezar, una revisión por pares, ¿sí? Una revisión por pares, y el objetivo al final de la clase es que puedan determinar si tienen correcciones para sus ensayos. Mi nombre es Sarah Brown Wessling. Soy profesora de inglés de secundaria en la Escuela Secundaria Johnston, de Johnston, Iowa. Giren hacia alguien que esté cerca. Díganle qué cadena lógica es necesario demostrar. Creo que hay una diferencia para los profesores entre lo abstracto de cómo vemos nuestra práctica y luego la realidad concreta de la misma. Bien, me gustaría que traigan sus artículos. Creo que el video nos ofrece un cierto grado de realidad. Uno no puede negar lo que se ve en el video, hay mucho que aprender de eso, y hay muchas maneras de crecer en la profesión viendo esto. Tengo una cámara de video y un pequeño trípode e invertí en esta pequeña lente gran angular. Al principio de la clase coloco la cámara en el fondo de la clase. No es una toma perfecta. No capta todo lo que sucede. Pero puedo oír el audio. Puedo ver mucho. Puedo aprender mucho con el video. De modo que ha sido una herramienta simple pero potente para analizar la clase. Bien, primero veamos la larga, ¿sí? Cuando termino de grabar, lo pongo en la computadora, lo repaso y tomo notas. Si no escribo, no las recuerdo. Así que tomar notas es parte de mi elaboración mental y descubro cosas conforme escribo. Me ha servido para mi crecimiento personal y para mi propia reflexión sobre la estrategia de enseñanza, la metodología, la gestión del aula y los diferentes aspectos de la clase. Me alegro de que ya se haya aplicado este método para comparar, en cierto modo, lo que funciona y lo que no. Creo que ese video expone muchos elementos intrínsecos a la docencia de forma que nos ayuda a entender, y ayuda a la comunidad más amplia a entender, de qué se trata en realidad este complejo trabajo. Creo que es una forma de ilustrar cosas que no se pueden transmitir en un plan de estudios, cosas que no pueden transmitirse en una norma, cosas que ni siquiera a veces se pueden transmitir en un libro de pedagogía. Muy bien, que tengan un buen fin de semana. Hasta la próxima. [Todas las clases pueden ser así] (Aplausos) Bill Gates: Nos gustaría que algún día las aulas de EE.UU. sean como esa. Pero todavía hay trabajo por hacer. Diagnosticar las áreas de mejora docente es la mitad de la batalla. También tenemos que darles las herramientas necesarias para actuar frente al diagnóstico. Si uno sabe que tiene que mejorar la forma de enseñar fracciones, debería poder ver un video de la persona que mejor enseña fracciones en el mundo. Pero construir esta retroalimentación para el profesor y mejorar el sistema no será fácil. Por ejemplo, sé que algunos profesores no se sienten inmediatamente cómodos con la idea de una cámara en el aula. Es comprensible, pero nuestra experiencia con MEE sugiere que si el profesor gestiona el proceso, si son ellos quienes graban las clases, y ellos eligen los cursos que quieren publicar, muchos estarán ansiosos de participar. Construir este sistema requerirá además una inversión considerable. Nuestra fundación estima que podría costar hasta USD 5000 millones. Es una suma grande, pero puesta en perspectiva, es menos del 2 % de lo que se paga en salarios a los docentes. Las ventajas para los profesores serían fenomenales. Finalmente tendríamos una forma de darles retroalimentación así como los medios para hacer algo al respecto. Pero este sistema tendría incluso un beneficio más importante para el país. Nos colocaría en una senda segura en la que nuestros estudiantes tendrían buena formación, encontrarían una carrera satisfactoria y gratificante, y tendrían la oportunidad de cumplir sus sueños. Esto no solo mejoraría el éxito de nuestro país, sino que lo haría más justo, también. Estoy muy entusiasmado con la oportunidad de darles a nuestros profesores el apoyo que quieren y merecen. Espero que Uds. también. Gracias. (Aplausos)